<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <title>Sensitivity of Coastal Environments and Wildlife to Spilled Oil: South Florida: ESIL (Environmental Sensitivity Index Shoreline Types - Lines)</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <onlink>http://myfwc.com/research</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2001%20-%20Rocky%20-%20Solid%20ManMade%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2002%20-%20Exposed%20Platform%20-%20Scarp%20-%20Slope%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2003%20-%20Fine%20-%20Medium%20Sand%20Beach%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2004%20-%20Coarse%20Sand%20Beach%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2005%20-%20Sand%20-%20Gravel%20Beach%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2006%20-%20Gravel%20-%20Riprap%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2007%20-%20Exposed%20Tidal%20Flats%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2008%20-%20Bedrock%20-%20Mud%20-%20Clay%20-%20ManMade%20-%20Riprap%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2009%20-%20Sheltered%20Tidal%20Flats%20-%20Low%20Banks%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2010A%20-%20Salt%20-%20Brackish%20Marsh%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2010B%20-%20Freshwater%20Marsh%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2010C%20-%20Swamp%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
                <onlink>http://atoll.floridamarine.org/Data/KMZ_files/ESI%20-%2010D%20-%20Scrub%20-%20Shrub%20Wetlands%20-%20FL.kmz</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>This data set contains vector lines representing the shoreline and coastal habitats of South Florida (2012), Florida Panhandle (2011/2012), and the rest of Florida (2003) classified according to the Environmental Sensitivity Index (ESI) classification system. This data set comprises a portion of the ESI data for Florida. ESI data characterize the marine and coastal environments and wildlife by their sensitivity to spilled oil. The ESI data include information for three main components: shoreline habitats, sensitive biological resources, and human-use resources. See also the ESIP and HYDRO data layers, part of the larger Statewide Florida Composite ESI database, for additional ESI information. Environmental Sensitivity Index (ESI) is more properly known as "Sensitivity of Coastal Habitats and Wildlife to Spilled Oil" Atlases. The term "ESI" is often used in reference to the whole dataset, but the term "ESI" is really a reference to the classification system of shoreline types known as Environmental Sensitivity Index, that classifies a shoreline on a scale from 1 to 10 based upon overall sensitivity to spilled oil. FWRI contracted out updates to Florida's ESI data for the Panhandle and South Florida in the years 2010 through early 2013. However, FWRI wanted and needed a statewide product for use within the Marine Resources Geographic Information System (MRGIS) and the Florida Marine Spill Analysis System (FMSAS). This data set is a compilation of the most recent ESI mapping for each area of Florida.</abstract>
            <purpose>To visually represent the most recent Environmental Sensitivity Index data available for each area within the state of Florida.</purpose>
            <supplinf>Prior to July 1, 2004, the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute (FWRI) was known as the Florida Marine Research Institute (FMRI). The institute name has not been changed in historical data sets or references to work completed by the Florida Marine Research Institute. The institute name has been changed in references to ongoing research, new research, and contact information.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <mdattim>
                    <sngdate>
                        <caldate>20130101</caldate>
                    </sngdate>
                    <sngdate>
                        <caldate>20030101</caldate>
                    </sngdate>
                    <sngdate>
                        <caldate>20120101</caldate>
                    </sngdate>
                </mdattim>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>publication date</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>As needed</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-87.533865</westbc>
                <eastbc>-79.8821</eastbc>
                <northbc>30.794674</northbc>
                <southbc>24.480442</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>User</themekt>
                <themekey>mapping</themekey>
                <themekey>ESI</themekey>
                <themekey>GIS</themekey>
                <themekey>oil spill</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
                <themekey>environment</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
                <themekey>environment</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>FWC Place</placekt>
                <placekey>statewide</placekey>
                <placekey>Florida</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>These data are unrestricted. Where possible, always acquire this dataset directly from FWC as other sources may have altered the original data.</accconst>
        <useconst>Users are encouraged to read and fully comprehend the metadata record prior to using these data. Please acknowledge the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission (FWC) as the data source for any products developed from these data. Users should be aware that comparison with other data sets for the same area may be inaccurate due to inconsistencies resulting from changes in mapping conventions, data collection techniques, and computer processes over time. FWC shall not be liable for improper or incorrect use of these data.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                    <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                    <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>33701</postal>
                    <country>AF</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>Prepared by Research Planning, Inc., Columbia, South Carolina for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service, Office of Response and Restoration, Emergency Response Division, Seattle, Washington. This project was supported by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Response and Restoration (OR&amp;R), Emergency Response Division (ERD), Seattle, Washington, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), United States Coast Guard (USCG), Office of Incident Management and Preparedness Washington, D.C. and the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute (FWRI), Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, St. Petersburg, Florida.</datacred>
        <secinfo>
            <secsys>FWRI-DC</secsys>
            <sechandl>Available without restriction</sechandl>
        </secinfo>
        <native/>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>A multi-stage error checking process is used to verify both attribute accuracy and logical consistency throughout data production. The process includes a standardized data entry methodology, hardcopy data review by in-house and external resource experts, a final Quality Assurance/Quality Control (QA/QC) process, and multiple automated logical consistency checks. Quantitative data (such as densities, counts, abundances, or concentrations) provided by resource experts for inclusion in the data set may vary widely in attribute accuracy, depending upon the methodology used to collect and compile such data. See process step for additional QA/QC performed by FWRI to reconcile the multiple data sources used to create the composite data set.</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>A multi-stage error checking process, described in the above Attribute_Accuracy_Report, is used to verify both attribute accuracy and logical consistency throughout data production. This process includes multiple automated logical consistency checks that test the files for missing or duplicate data, rules for proper coding, GIS topological consistencies (such as dangles, unnecessary node, etc.), and SQL SERVER(R) to ARC/INFO(R) consistencies. A final review is made by the GIS manager. See process step for additional logical consistency checks performed by FWRI to reconcile the multiple data sources used to create the composite data set.</logic>
        <complete>These data represent coastal shorelines and habitats classified according to the Environmental Sensitivity Index (ESI) classification system. See also the ESIP and HYDRO data layers, part of the larger South Florida ESI database, for additional ESI information.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>The spatial location of the ESI shoreline was developed from pre-existing digital sources and reflects the positional accuracy of these original data.</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20130401</pubdate>
                        <title>Sensitivity of Coastal Environments and Wildlife to Spilled Oil: South Florida</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20130401</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Sensitivity of Coastal Environments and Wildlife to Spilled Oil: South Florida</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Data in South Florida</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20120801</pubdate>
                        <title>Sensitivity of Coastal Environments and Wildlife to Spilled Oil: Florida Panhandle</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20120801</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Sensitivity of Coastal Environments and Wildlife to Spilled Oil: Florida Panhandle</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Data in the Florida Panhandle</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20030901</pubdate>
                        <title>Gulf-Wide Information System, Coast of Florida (Entire) and the Lower St. Johns River</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <mdattim>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20030901</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20010301</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                        </mdattim>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Gulf-Wide Information System, Coast of Florida (Entire) and the Lower St. Johns River</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Data in ares of Florida that were not included in the 2012 Panhandle or 2013 South Florida ESI updates. ESI line, polygon, hydro, and terrestrial mammals data were from 2003 other ESI data types were from 2000, including birds, bird nests, habitats, fish, invertebrates, marine mammals, management, reptiles, socioeconomic.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Data have been sorted so that the draw order is from Upper left to lower right.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</cntorg>
                            <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                        </cntorgp>
                        <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                            <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                            <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                            <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                            <state>Florida</state>
                            <postal>33701</postal>
                            <country>AF</country>
                        </cntaddr>
                        <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                        <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>PROCESS STEPS IN MAPJOINING NEW AND OLD ESI INTO A COMPOSITE STATEWIDE ESI DATASET: Tools Used: ArcGIS for Desktop Advanced License: ArcMap v. 10.0, Service Pack 5, XTools Pro Version 9.1.956 1. Data gathering and QA/QC: ESI Statewide 2003, ESI Birds from 2000, Panhandle ESI from 2012, South Florida ESI from 2013. All original data as COVERAGES were converted to File Geodatabase (fGDB) feature classes. Biological data sets as region polygon data within coverages were exported to file geodatabase Feature Classes. Info tables were exported to fGDB tables. 2. Schema validation: Differences across 2000, 2003, 2012, and 2013 datasets were noted. The overall schema from 2013 ESI (for South Florida) was used to create the final composite ESI file geodatabase schema design, though some modifications were made to this schema to accommodate concatenation and longer field character limits as mentioned below. 3. Align RARNUMS to be unique to each dataset by year produced (2000, 2003, 2012, 2013). This required schema change to increase RARNUM field length to accommodate a larger integer field. 4. Align G_SOURCE, A_SOURCE, S_SOURCE, and SOURCEID to be unique to each dataset by year produced (2000, 2003, 2012, 2013). This required schema change to increase source id fields lengths to accommodate a larger integer field. 5. Compare SPECIES tables across datasets, eliminate duplicates, merge into composite SPECIES table. Validate species scientific name is current across all species. Several were noted to be using "older" species scientific name. These were corrected in the final composite SPECIES table. 6. Compare STATUS table across datasets, eliminate duplicates, merge into composite STATUS table in 2012/2013 STATUS table schema, establish relate to SPECIES table and then validate T/E/C status across all of the T/E/C species as compared to T/E species list prepared by FWC in 2012. It should be noted that there are significant differences between the STATUS table used in 2003 and prior ESI data versus later editions of the STATUS table. These differences have been reconciled. 7. File Geodatabases were created and prepared, one for each source edition of ESI geodata, and one for the final composite ESI. Beginning with the statewide 2003 ESI Biology layers and the RARNUM field for each layer, the RARNUM was recalculated to append "2003" onto the front of the original RARNUM. With RARNUM being a "double" field, this was done by using the field calculator in an edit session like this; RARNUM = RARNUM + 20030000, as no RARNUM was longer than 4 digits in any of the biology feature classes. This same edit was then performed on the RARNUM field within the BIORES table and relationships were validated for intactness. Within the BIORES table, there were four fields for source identification; G_SOURCE (geographic source), S_SOURCE (seasonality source), GEO_SRC (geographic source), and SEASON_SRC (seasonality source) depending on the year of the data. These fields were reconciled in the final composite data file. Each of these fields needed to be recalculated in the same manner as for RARNUM to key them into the edition of the dataset so that each would remain unique once merged into the composite ESI geodata statewide. Additionally in the BIORES table there is an important key field named ELE_SPE_SEA which is a composite code generated from the ELEMENT, SPECIES, and SEASONAL identifiers. This field needed to be modified by extending the field length from 8 to 16 characters (Text/String values). In order to retain the EL_SPE_SEA values as unique to each atlas edition, the original values of each ELE_SPE_SEA had the year of the atlas concatenated onto the END of it. In example, ELE_SPE_SEA of R0000501 became R00005012003, indicating ELEMENT = Reptile, SPECIES ID = 00005 (Leatherback Sea Turtle), SEASON_ID = 01 (listed as March-July) for the 2003 ESI Atlas (Statewide ESI 2003). The same attribute table schema modifications were performed on the 2012 geodata (Panhandle Florida), 2013 geodata (South Florida), and on the BIRDS (region.bio) geodata and tables for 2000. IMPORTANT NOTE: BIRDS (region.bio) and NESTS (points) from 2000 were used instead of the 2003 geodata because the updates to each of these layers and associated tables performed in 2003 only included a subset of the species that were included in 2000, so thus it was deemed that the 2000 data was superior and would be used instead. 8. Using the "Erase Features" tool in XTools Pro and the "Study Area" polygons of the 2012 Panhandle Florida ESI and 2013 South Florida ESI geodata, the areas of the statewide 2003 ESI geodata were systematically erased to prepare that data for merging with the newer geodata. The result was a fGDB of ESI geodata for the areas of Florida NOT updated in either the Panhandle or South Florida updates performed from 2010 to 2013 that additionally had the table and attribute modifications needed in order for the data to be smoothly mapjoined with all of the newer ESI data. 9. Using ArcCatalog and a copy of the South Florida ESI geodata and tables in a fGDB as a start, each of the layers within the Panhandle ESI were systematically imported, including tables, into the template "Composite Statewide" ESI file geodatabase. Once complete, each layer was viewed in comparison with its counterpart layer in the "erased 2003" geodata to ensure that no temporal overlap would occur in the data merge. 10. Using ArcCatalog, the "erased 2003" geodata were imported systematically into the merged Panhandle and South Florida ESI geodata (except for BIRDS and NESTS which were prepared separately using the geodata from 2000) to produce an "almost complete" Statewide Composite ESI" file geodatabase. Finally the appropriately and similarly prepared BIRDS and NESTS geodata and table records from 2000 were imported. In certain circumstances, some "cross-field mapping" was performed as needed to ensure that appropriate values were carried over into the final data schemas. This was largely done in the STATUS table because the schemas are radically different between 2003 data and the current (final) STATUS table schema used in the "Composite Statewide" 2013 geodata. QA and QC were then performed extensively using as series of Joins, Relates, and Queries, validating the soundness and completeness of the overall dataset.</procdesc>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>ESIL_2013_Statewide</enttypl>
                <enttypd>ESI shoreline coding - lines</enttypd>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>G_SOURCE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Geographic source integer identifier that links to records in the SOURCES data table.</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>VER_NEED</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Refers to whether field verification is needed (2003 data)</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>VER_DATE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date of field verification (2003 data)</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Research Planning, Inc.</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ENVIR</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Type of regional environment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NOAA ESI Guidelines</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>E</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Estuarine</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>NOAA ESI Guidelines</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID_12</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>MOST_SENS</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Most sensitive ESI code present for a line segment.</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>MSTSENDES</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Description of most sensitive ESI code present for a line segment.</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FREQUENCY</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHRT_DESC</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Short description of all ESI codes present for a line segment.</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>A_SOURCE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Attribute source integer identifier that links to records in the SOURCES data table.</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LINE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Type of geographic feature.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NOAA ESI Guidelines</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>H</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Hydrography</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>NOAA ESI Guidelines</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CASE_</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ESI</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The item ESI contains values representing the ESI shoreline type. In many cases shorelines are ranked with multiple codes, such as "6B/3A" (listed landward to seaward from left to right). The first code, "6B", is the most landward shoreline type and the second code, "3A", is the shoreline type closest to the water. Singular shoreline types are listed below. No multiple codes are listed, but all multiple codes included in the data set can be assembled from the codes described. The ESI rankings progress from low to high susceptibility to oil spills. To determine the sensitivity of a particular intertidal shoreline habitat, the following factors are integrated: 1) Shoreline type (substrate, grain size, tidal elevation, origin); 2) Exposure to wave and tidal energy; 3) Biological productivity and sensitivity; 4) Ease of cleanup. Prediction of the behavior and persistence of oil in intertidal habitats is based on an understanding of the dynamics of the coastal environments, not just the substrate type and grain size. The intensity of energy expended upon a shoreline by wave action, tidal currents, and river currents directly affects the persistence of stranded oil. The need for shoreline cleanup activities is determined, in part, by the slowness of natural processes in removal of oil stranded on the shoreline. The potential for biological injury, and ease of cleanup of spilled oil are also important factors in the ESI ranking. Generally speaking, areas exposed to high levels of physical energy, such as wave action and tidal currents, and low biological activity rank low on the scale, whereas sheltered areas with associated high biological activity have the highest ranking.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NOAA ESI Guidelines</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>1B</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Exposed, Solid Man-made Structures</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>NOAA ESI Guidelines</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>DESC_</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Description of all ESI codes present for a line segment.</attrdef>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                    <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                    <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>33701</postal>
                    <country>AF</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>This data set is in the public domain, and the recipient may not assert any proprietary rights thereto nor represent it to anyone as other than a Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission produced data set; it is provided "as-is" without warranty of any kind, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. The user assumes all responsibility for the accuracy and suitability of this data set for a specific application. In no event will the staff of the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission be liable for any damages, including lost profits, lost savings, or other incidental or consequential damages arising from the use of or the inability to use this data set.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>SHP</formname>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>http://myfwc.com/research</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>None. However, persons or organizations requesting information must provide transfer media if FTP is not available and must pay express shipping costs if express shipping is required.</fees>
            <ordering>Contact GIS Librarian by e-mail, telephone, or letter explaining which products are needed and providing a brief description of how the products will be used. Also, provide name and address of the person or organization requesting the products.</ordering>
            <turnarnd>Usually within 10 business days, although, complex requests may take longer</turnarnd>
        </stdorder>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20130905</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                    <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                    <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>33701</postal>
                    <country>AF</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
        <metac>No restrictions on metadata</metac>
        <metuc>Metadata must be distributed with the data set.</metuc>
        <metsi>
            <metscs>FWRI-MC</metscs>
            <metshd>Metadata must be distributed with the data set.</metshd>
        </metsi>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
